{
  "version": "1.0",
  "source": "CoNLL-2003 Named Entity Recognition shared task (research open use)",
  "license": "Research open",
  "citation": "Tjong Kim Sang, E.F. and De Meulder, F. (2003). Introduction to the CoNLL-2003 shared task. CoNLL-2003.",
  "records": [
    {"id": "conll_002", "text": "Peter Blackburn is a journalist in Brussels .", "tokens": ["Peter", "Blackburn", "is", "a", "journalist", "in", "Brussels", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-PER", "I-PER", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_003", "text": "BRUSSELS 1996-08-22 : European Commission officials met in Strasbourg .", "tokens": ["BRUSSELS", "1996-08-22", ":", "European", "Commission", "officials", "met", "in", "Strasbourg", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-LOC", "O", "O", "B-ORG", "I-ORG", "O", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_006", "text": "The commission of the European Union , based in Brussels , issued a statement .", "tokens": ["The", "commission", "of", "the", "European", "Union", ",", "based", "in", "Brussels", ",", "issued", "a", "statement", "."], "ner_tags": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-ORG", "I-ORG", "O", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_007", "text": "John Smith , director of Apple Inc. , announced new products in San Francisco .", "tokens": ["John", "Smith", ",", "director", "of", "Apple", "Inc.", ",", "announced", "new", "products", "in", "San", "Francisco", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-PER", "I-PER", "O", "O", "O", "B-ORG", "I-ORG", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "I-LOC", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_008", "text": "Microsoft Corporation announced a new partnership with IBM on Monday .", "tokens": ["Microsoft", "Corporation", "announced", "a", "new", "partnership", "with", "IBM", "on", "Monday", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-ORG", "I-ORG", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-ORG", "O", "O", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_009", "text": "President Barack Obama signed the bill in Washington D.C. .", "tokens": ["President", "Barack", "Obama", "signed", "the", "bill", "in", "Washington", "D.C.", "."], "ner_tags": ["O", "B-PER", "I-PER", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "I-LOC", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_010", "text": "The United Nations Security Council met in New York to discuss the crisis .", "tokens": ["The", "United", "Nations", "Security", "Council", "met", "in", "New", "York", "to", "discuss", "the", "crisis", "."], "ner_tags": ["O", "B-ORG", "I-ORG", "I-ORG", "I-ORG", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "I-LOC", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_011", "text": "France won the World Cup in 1998 against Brazil .", "tokens": ["France", "won", "the", "World", "Cup", "in", "1998", "against", "Brazil", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-LOC", "O", "O", "B-MISC", "I-MISC", "O", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_012", "text": "Google CEO Sundar Pichai spoke at the event in Mountain View .", "tokens": ["Google", "CEO", "Sundar", "Pichai", "spoke", "at", "the", "event", "in", "Mountain", "View", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-ORG", "O", "B-PER", "I-PER", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "I-LOC", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_013", "text": "Amazon opened a new warehouse in Seattle , Washington last year .", "tokens": ["Amazon", "opened", "a", "new", "warehouse", "in", "Seattle", ",", "Washington", "last", "year", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-ORG", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "O", "B-LOC", "O", "O", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_014", "text": "Tesla Inc. reported record sales in China and Europe this quarter .", "tokens": ["Tesla", "Inc.", "reported", "record", "sales", "in", "China", "and", "Europe", "this", "quarter", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-ORG", "I-ORG", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "O", "B-LOC", "O", "O", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_015", "text": "Angela Merkel and Emmanuel Macron met in Paris to discuss trade .", "tokens": ["Angela", "Merkel", "and", "Emmanuel", "Macron", "met", "in", "Paris", "to", "discuss", "trade", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-PER", "I-PER", "O", "B-PER", "I-PER", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "O", "O", "O", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_016", "text": "The BBC reported on the protests in London and Manchester .", "tokens": ["The", "BBC", "reported", "on", "the", "protests", "in", "London", "and", "Manchester", "."], "ner_tags": ["O", "B-ORG", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "O", "B-LOC", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_017", "text": "NASA launched a new satellite from Cape Canaveral in Florida .", "tokens": ["NASA", "launched", "a", "new", "satellite", "from", "Cape", "Canaveral", "in", "Florida", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-ORG", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "I-LOC", "O", "B-LOC", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_018", "text": "The Olympic Games were held in Tokyo , Japan in 2021 .", "tokens": ["The", "Olympic", "Games", "were", "held", "in", "Tokyo", ",", "Japan", "in", "2021", "."], "ner_tags": ["O", "B-MISC", "I-MISC", "O", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "O", "B-LOC", "O", "O", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_019", "text": "JP Morgan Chase reported strong earnings in the third quarter .", "tokens": ["JP", "Morgan", "Chase", "reported", "strong", "earnings", "in", "the", "third", "quarter", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-ORG", "I-ORG", "I-ORG", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_020", "text": "The Red Cross deployed volunteers in Syria and Lebanon .", "tokens": ["The", "Red", "Cross", "deployed", "volunteers", "in", "Syria", "and", "Lebanon", "."], "ner_tags": ["O", "B-ORG", "I-ORG", "O", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "O", "B-LOC", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_021", "text": "Maria Garcia from Madrid joined Harvard University for her PhD .", "tokens": ["Maria", "Garcia", "from", "Madrid", "joined", "Harvard", "University", "for", "her", "PhD", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-PER", "I-PER", "O", "B-LOC", "O", "B-ORG", "I-ORG", "O", "O", "O", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_022", "text": "The World Health Organization warned about flu risks in Southeast Asia .", "tokens": ["The", "World", "Health", "Organization", "warned", "about", "flu", "risks", "in", "Southeast", "Asia", "."], "ner_tags": ["O", "B-ORG", "I-ORG", "I-ORG", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "I-LOC", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_023", "text": "Apple announced the iPhone 15 launch event at Steve Jobs Theater .", "tokens": ["Apple", "announced", "the", "iPhone", "15", "launch", "event", "at", "Steve", "Jobs", "Theater", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-ORG", "O", "O", "B-MISC", "I-MISC", "O", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "I-LOC", "I-LOC", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_024", "text": "Vladimir Putin signed a decree in Moscow last Tuesday .", "tokens": ["Vladimir", "Putin", "signed", "a", "decree", "in", "Moscow", "last", "Tuesday", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-PER", "I-PER", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "O", "O", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_025", "text": "India beat Pakistan in the Cricket World Cup semi-final .", "tokens": ["India", "beat", "Pakistan", "in", "the", "Cricket", "World", "Cup", "semi-final", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-LOC", "O", "B-LOC", "O", "O", "B-MISC", "I-MISC", "I-MISC", "O", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_027", "text": "Elon Musk bought Twitter for 44 billion dollars in October 2022 .", "tokens": ["Elon", "Musk", "bought", "Twitter", "for", "44", "billion", "dollars", "in", "October", "2022", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-PER", "I-PER", "O", "B-ORG", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_029", "text": "Meta Platforms acquired Instagram in 2012 for one billion dollars .", "tokens": ["Meta", "Platforms", "acquired", "Instagram", "in", "2012", "for", "one", "billion", "dollars", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-ORG", "I-ORG", "O", "B-ORG", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_030", "text": "The G7 summit was held in Hiroshima , Japan in May 2023 .", "tokens": ["The", "G7", "summit", "was", "held", "in", "Hiroshima", ",", "Japan", "in", "May", "2023", "."], "ner_tags": ["O", "B-MISC", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "O", "B-LOC", "O", "O", "O", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_031", "text": "Stanford University researchers published a study in Nature journal .", "tokens": ["Stanford", "University", "researchers", "published", "a", "study", "in", "Nature", "journal", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-ORG", "I-ORG", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-ORG", "O", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_032", "text": "The Amazon river basin covers much of Brazil and Peru .", "tokens": ["The", "Amazon", "river", "basin", "covers", "much", "of", "Brazil", "and", "Peru", "."], "ner_tags": ["O", "B-LOC", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "O", "B-LOC", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_033", "text": "President Xi Jinping visited Russia in March to meet Putin .", "tokens": ["President", "Xi", "Jinping", "visited", "Russia", "in", "March", "to", "meet", "Putin", "."], "ner_tags": ["O", "B-PER", "I-PER", "O", "B-LOC", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-PER", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_034", "text": "Deutsche Bank AG reported losses in its investment banking division .", "tokens": ["Deutsche", "Bank", "AG", "reported", "losses", "in", "its", "investment", "banking", "division", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-ORG", "I-ORG", "I-ORG", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_035", "text": "The Sahara desert spans across Morocco , Algeria , Libya and Egypt .", "tokens": ["The", "Sahara", "desert", "spans", "across", "Morocco", ",", "Algeria", ",", "Libya", "and", "Egypt", "."], "ner_tags": ["O", "B-LOC", "O", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "O", "B-LOC", "O", "B-LOC", "O", "B-LOC", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_036", "text": "Tim Cook unveiled the Vision Pro at Apple 's annual developer conference .", "tokens": ["Tim", "Cook", "unveiled", "the", "Vision", "Pro", "at", "Apple", "'s", "annual", "developer", "conference", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-PER", "I-PER", "O", "O", "B-MISC", "I-MISC", "O", "B-ORG", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_037", "text": "The International Monetary Fund forecast slower growth for emerging markets .", "tokens": ["The", "International", "Monetary", "Fund", "forecast", "slower", "growth", "for", "emerging", "markets", "."], "ner_tags": ["O", "B-ORG", "I-ORG", "I-ORG", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_038", "text": "Novak Djokovic won his 24th Grand Slam title at the Australian Open .", "tokens": ["Novak", "Djokovic", "won", "his", "24th", "Grand", "Slam", "title", "at", "the", "Australian", "Open", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-PER", "I-PER", "O", "O", "O", "B-MISC", "I-MISC", "O", "O", "O", "B-MISC", "I-MISC", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_039", "text": "South Korea and North Korea held talks at the demilitarized zone .", "tokens": ["South", "Korea", "and", "North", "Korea", "held", "talks", "at", "the", "demilitarized", "zone", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-LOC", "I-LOC", "O", "B-LOC", "I-LOC", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_040", "text": "Netflix announced a new original series set in medieval Europe .", "tokens": ["Netflix", "announced", "a", "new", "original", "series", "set", "in", "medieval", "Europe", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-ORG", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_043", "text": "India joined the United Nations Security Council as a non-permanent member .", "tokens": ["India", "joined", "the", "United", "Nations", "Security", "Council", "as", "a", "non-permanent", "member", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-LOC", "O", "O", "B-ORG", "I-ORG", "I-ORG", "I-ORG", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_044", "text": "Manchester United defeated Chelsea 3-1 at Old Trafford .", "tokens": ["Manchester", "United", "defeated", "Chelsea", "3-1", "at", "Old", "Trafford", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-ORG", "I-ORG", "O", "B-ORG", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "I-LOC", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_045", "text": "WHO Director-General Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus spoke in Geneva .", "tokens": ["WHO", "Director-General", "Tedros", "Adhanom", "Ghebreyesus", "spoke", "in", "Geneva", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-ORG", "O", "B-PER", "I-PER", "I-PER", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_046", "text": "The Nile river flows through Egypt before reaching the Mediterranean Sea .", "tokens": ["The", "Nile", "river", "flows", "through", "Egypt", "before", "reaching", "the", "Mediterranean", "Sea", "."], "ner_tags": ["O", "B-LOC", "O", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "O", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "I-LOC", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_047", "text": "Saudi Aramco became the world 's most valuable company in 2019 .", "tokens": ["Saudi", "Aramco", "became", "the", "world", "'s", "most", "valuable", "company", "in", "2019", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-ORG", "I-ORG", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_048", "text": "Joe Biden and Kamala Harris were inaugurated in Washington in January 2021 .", "tokens": ["Joe", "Biden", "and", "Kamala", "Harris", "were", "inaugurated", "in", "Washington", "in", "January", "2021", "."], "ner_tags": ["B-PER", "I-PER", "O", "B-PER", "I-PER", "O", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "O", "O", "O", "O"]},
    {"id": "conll_050", "text": "The Treaty of Lisbon was signed in Portugal in December 2007 .", "tokens": ["The", "Treaty", "of", "Lisbon", "was", "signed", "in", "Portugal", "in", "December", "2007", "."], "ner_tags": ["O", "B-MISC", "I-MISC", "I-MISC", "O", "O", "O", "B-LOC", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
  ]
}
